adavidson@pm.me 570-412-3528

https://github.com/ananaso

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software engineering professional with experience developing and designing web applications using TypeScript, React, CSS, Kotlin, and Spring. Adept at developing and deploying backend and frontend systems, responding to and resolving bugs and production issues in low-visibility environment, and identifying further areas of improvement in existing codebases.

SKILLS_

Languages: CSS, Kotlin, LATEX, TypeScript

Software: Docker, GNU/Linux, MySQL, React, Spring Framework

Practices: Extreme Programming, Test-driven development

Foreign Languages: German (A2/B1), Esperanto (A1)

WORK HISTORY

Full-stack Software Engineer, US Space Force | Los Angeles, CA

Jan 2022 – present

- Developed and sustained two full-stack applications for 1200+ space command and control users requiring worldwide availability
- Practiced test-driven development at the unit, integration, and end-to-end levels to ensure consistent code quality in continuous integration environment
- Analyzed existing software implementations to identify areas of improvement
- Participated in requirements gathering for high-visibility executive-directed action to solidify prerequisites and determine best technical solution to meet user needs

GPS Mission Director, US Air Force/US Space Force | Los Angeles, CA

Apr 2020 – Jun 2021

- · Commanded 12-member team for readiness events and launch & early orbit operations (L&EO)
- \cdot Conducted L&EO for SV04

Project Manager, US Air Force/US Space Force | Los Angeles, CA

Nov 2019 – Dec 2021

- · Planned, scheduled, and negotiated \$28M follow-on for \$34M project
- · Monitored project performance to identify areas of improvement and make adjustments
- · Coordinated and led cross-functional team of 8 to resolve project issues and mitigate risks
- · Oversaw 30+ member team of contractors performing software development
- · Provided detailed project status updates to stakeholders and executive management

Robot Programmer Intern, RT Leaders | Munich, Germany

Jun 2017 – Dec 2017

- Worked with 5-member multidisciplinary team to design and build bespoke robotic cell battery construction machine, increasing customer safety and productivity
- Planned and implemented operations for 12 FANUC unites across a manufacturing line to fit a new product design

Software Development Intern, RIT Comp. Eng. Dept. | Rochester, NY

Dec 2016 – May 2017

- Researched and implemented networking protocols within a virtual domain for realization of real-world radio use cases, using a synthesis of C++ and Python
- Worked independently with regular progress updates to customer and supervisor

- Supervise 4+ student employees per shift
- Ensure compliance with food safety procedures
- Manage customer problems and complaints

EDUCATION_____

Rochester Institute of Technology | Rochester, NY

- Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering, May 2019
- Minor in Military Studies and Leadership, May 2019
- GPA 3.55

Supra Coders Software Development Immersive | US Space Force

Oct 2020 - Apr 2021

- 3-month full stack development bootcamp with Defensive Cyber Operations Satellite follow-on assignment
- Configured Hack-A-Sat network with Puppet
- Developed COSMOS TT&C protocol decoder

PROJECTS.....

AT-AT - Aggregate Tasker Administration Tool

- Proof-of-Concept to replace Department of Defense's Tasker Management Tool
- Designed and implemented tasker inbox view/response features and accompanying database and API
- Built with Javascript, Express, PostgreSQL, React, and AstroUXDS CSS

Low Cost Fundus Camera | Senior Design

- Designed low-cost functional modern fundus camera capable of capturing screening quality retinal images
- Interfaced Raspberry Pi with linear actuators, motor HAT, and controllable LEDs
- Programmed user interface in PyQt

Semi-autonomous Cell Battery Constructor

- Planned and implemented operations for FANUC R-30iB to construct experimental cell batteries
- Designed semi-autonomous function for space-constrained, pumped argon environment

USAF Ribbon Rack Visualizer | Personal Project

- Developed PyQt application for visualizing ribbon racks with proper order of precedence.
- Created with option to extend support to other branches of the military.

Genesee River Raft | Personal Project

- Constructed raft by hand from fallen timber and rope
- Successfully floated it from RIT to the University of Rochester boathouse

COMMENDATIONS.

Boy Scouts of America

- Eagle Scout, Computer Sustainability and Recycling Drive
- Order of the Arrow: Vigil Honor

National German Honor Society

- Chapter President, 2018-2019